

Farzana Azad-

AVA DEVELOPER





- 4625 Commons Park Dr. New Albany, OH
- Linkedin.com/in/Farzana-azad-hussain-01b065144
- gitthub.com/Farzana01

TECH SKILLS

JAVA
CSS
HTML
GIT/GITHUB
JAVASCRIPT
LIBRARIES/API
Databases & SQL
AGILE DEVELOPMENT
Object-Oriented Programming

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE Business Administration FRANKLIN University 2004–2008

> CERTIFICATION We Can Code IT August 2017

VOLUNTEER

New Albany Plain Local Schools 4th grade Math

BALA foundation Stage manager, Program Coordinator, Sunday school teacher

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Recently completed an immersive Java developer Bootcamp at We Can Code IT. Aside from learning Java, also worked with databases (SQL) and front-end technologies (JSP, HTML/CSS, JavaScript). Projects are available at github.com/Farzana01. In short, I am a critical thinker who challenges the status quo driving process and quality improvements.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Hedge Fund Analyst Citi Hedge Fund Services

Aug 2011- Sept 2014

- Assisted portfolio managers in formulating the training program for new employees
- Communicated the progress and results of IT project to client regularly
- Accurately managed hedge funds and increased client investment by \$10 million.
- Managed risk with compliance guidelines and avoided penalties.
- Supervised virtually a group of four in India. Responsibilities included overseeing the monthly processes to close books accurately and in a timely manner

Senior Portfolio Accountant Citi Alternative Investment Strategies

July 2009-Aug 2011

- Excellent communicator and adept at building strong working relationships with coworkers, management, and client.
- Effective in auditing- never settled for any answer or transaction that did not seem right.
- Excellent at sorting out connections and linkages within the organization to focus the audit approach
- Led process automation project and successfully decreased employee over-time hours from an average of 30 hours per week to just 7 hours per week. The company had saved \$80,000 per year.

Mutual Fund Accountant Citi Global Transaction Services

Feb 2008-July 2009

- Maintained 100% accuracy calculating the NAV daily reducing time of delay by 30% according to financial tracking analysis.
- Key contact between client and pricing team. Mentored and supervised peers throughout pricing processes and submitting to Reuters accurately and on time.
- Utilized exceptional customer service skills to attract and retain high-value customers.
- Promoted to maintain large cap mutual funds which ranged over \$200 billion.